Welcome to this local AI engineering podcast session.
Today, we are documenting practical inference workflows
on an AMD Strix Halo machine with 96 gigabytes of unified memory.
The focus is not only peak benchmark numbers,
but repeatable operations, stable scripts,
and logs that can be reviewed later.
In this episode, we summarize the current stack.
Image generation is handled by QnImage and multiple diffusion pipelines.
Vision language analysis is covered by Qn2.5VL.
Coding and chat endpoints are served through Lama.CPP with Vulkan Acceleration.
MCP examples demonstrate browser automation, spreadsheet operations,
and local Python plus shell execution.
A key reliability practice is resource cleanup.
Before each heavy run, we clear stale containers
and terminate non-essential high-memory leftovers.
After each test, we do the same cleanup again,
so one run does not poison the next run.
This sounds simple, but it is usually the difference
between stable overnight testing and random crashes.
For image quality, one interesting direction is post-processing.
Base generations can look plastic in skin texture and lighting.
A diffusion upskiller can improve detail,
but the safest configuration is often lower input size and conservative denoising.
When instability appears, we reduce step count,
disable risky attention paths, and keep every retry fully logged.
On the coding side, we are also testing staged, agentic workflows.
The pattern is to define interfaces first, then tests,
then skeleton methods, and only then implementation.
That structure keeps goals explicit and makes progress auditable.
It also reduces wasted token budget
because each iteration has a concrete pass or fail target.
Finally, this transcript itself is part of the reproducibility process.
We use it to generate a synthetic podcast-style audio sample,
then run speech-to-text and export subtitles as SRT.
That gives us an end-to-end, fully local validation path
for long-form audio generation and subtitle extraction.
If you can replay this exact pipeline from Scripps alone,
the documentation is doing its job.